selftrade.co.uk 2014-11-30

# 

    IMPORTANT INFORMATION
    Privacy Policy
                                                                                                                                                                           0845 0700 720
                                                                                                                                                                           selftrade.co.uk
       We recognise that personal information you provide to us must be stored and handled in a safe, secure
       manner in order to ensure that it remains confidential. This Privacy Policy sets out our strict confidentiality
       standards, which are designed to protect the information we hold regarding you and your Account.
       Equally, you can help us protect your confidential information by ensuring you take sensible steps to
       protect your information, both on and offline; you will find some helpful tips on the Security page of our
       Website - (This does not form part of our Terms and Conditions).
       Please bear in mind that:
       Selftrade provides you with a range of tools and information to help you make informed investment
       decisions, but does not provide investment advice. If you are in any doubt as to the risk or suitability of
       an investment or product, you should seek advice from an independent financial adviser.
       Definitions used in this Privacy Policy:
       Data Controller means an individual, company or other organisation who determine how and for what
       purpose Personal Data is processed. Selftrade acts as a Data Controller when processing Personal Data
       relating to our customers;
       Data Processor means any person or organisation which processes personal data on behalf of a Data
       Controller (except for an employee of the Data Controller);
       Data Subject means a person who can be identified by particular Personal Data. If you are a Selftrade
       customer, you are a Data Subject and we are responsible for processing your Personal Data;
       Personal Data means data which relates to a living person, who can be identified from the contents
       of that data, or from that data when is combined with information which is likely to come into the
       possession of the Data Controller; and
       Subject Access means the rights of Data Subjects, including to be told whether a Data Controller holds
       their Personal Data and to see a copy of it.
       1 - Your login details
       If you choose to access the secure areas of our Website (the internet website relating to Selftrade with
       the URL of www.selftrade.co.uk, or such other website as we may notify you of from time to time),
       which are designed for Members or Customers only, you are able to access these only with your login
       details (which are provided to you once your Account has been opened, and which only you, any joint
       holder or a person that you have authorised to operate the Account should know). Your login details
       should never be shared with anyone else and we recommend that any password or PIN you set is not
       easily guessable, and changed frequently (at least once a month).
       Because we cannot guarantee the confidentiality of information sent on the internet, you should never
       send your login details via email. Should you wish to contact us about your Dealing Account or Deposit
       Account, we recommend you do so via the secure message facility accessed from your online Account,
       which is encrypted and offers greater confidentiality.
       2 - How we may communicate with you
       A - Marketing communications
       Unless you have specified that you do not wish to receive such marketing communications, we may
       from time to time send you information regarding new products and promotions by email, post or
       SMS. Additionally, unless you have instructed us not to do so, we may occasionally also contact you by
       telephone regarding such products or promotions.
       You can specify that you do not wish to receive marketing emails from us by sending an email with
       “unsubscribe” in the subject field to info@selftrade.co.uk. If you have registered more than one email
Selftrade, Boatman’s House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA Tel: 0845 0700 720 Email: info@selftrade.co.uk www.selftrade.co.uk                                                                FS16 0914
Selftrade® is a trading name of Talos Securities Limited and registered trade mark of Boursorama. Talos Securities Limited is incorporated in England and Wales (Registration No. 4196325, Registered
Address: Boatman’s House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA) and is a member of the London Stock Exchange and ICAP Securities & Derivatives Exchange Limited (ISDX). Talos Securities Limited is
authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority (Register No. 208271).

       address with Selftrade, please list all your email addresses to be removed from our marketing emails
       in the body of the email. Please note that, while we will remove you from future marketing emails, any
       marketing emails already in production may still be received for a short time after you send us your request.
       If you have specified that you do not wish to receive marketing emails from us, we will still send you
       email messages which you specifically request to receive, or which relate to the provision of services
       you currently receive from us, such as notifications about annual and interim statements, important
       information about your account and regulatory information.
       If, having specified that you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us, you then wish to
       do so, you should email us at info@selftrade.co.uk or contact Customer Services on 0845 0700 720.
       B - Security of communications
       If you ever receive a communication from us that you are concerned may be from a third party
       impersonating Selftrade, please contact us immediately. If you are ever concerned that the person
       calling may not be from Selftrade, you can always ask to call us back on our Customer Services phone
       number 0845 0700 720 (or +442075174400 if you are calling from overseas).
       Selftrade will never ask for your full PIN number or password, but will ask security questions to confirm
       your identity before we can discuss matters relating to your Account.
       C - Surveys
       From time to time we may invite you to take part in an online survey. These surveys help us to monitor
       and improve the quality of service we provide and the range of services we offer. Participation is
       voluntary but we hope that you will take the opportunity, if invited to participate, to give us your
       feedback. All surveys are carried out in accordance with the Market Research Society’s Code of
       Practice. Should you not wish to be invited to participate in surveys, you should email us at info@
       selftrade.co.uk or contact Customer Services on 0845 0700 720.
       3 - How we comply with the Data Protection Act
       The Data Protection Act 1998 (“the Act”) regulates the processing of Personal Data. The Act seeks to
       protect your rights to your Personal Data by setting out (1) the conditions under which the processing
       of Personal Data is lawful, (2) the rights of Data Subjects and (3) the standards of quality that must be
       maintained. Where Selftrade acts as a Data Controller, we are committed to respecting the rights of
       Data Subjects and complying with the Act.
       A - Personal Data we may collect
       The information you give us in your application form, in other related documents or from your use of
       our Services, may contain your or another person’s Personal Data. If you provide us with information
       about another person, you confirm that they have appointed you to act for them, to consent to the
       processing of their Personal Data and that you have informed them of our identity and the Purposes
       (as set out below) for which their Personal Data will be processed.
       When you visit our Website we may automatically log your IP address, a unique identifier for your
       computer or other access device. We may use your IP address to identify you for Website security
       purposes only. For more information, please see the Security section of our Website - (This does not
       form part of our Terms and Conditions).
       By applying for our Services and/or providing Personal Data to us, whether or not you become a
       customer, you acknowledge that, in order to process any instruction or enquiry and carry out actions
       related to any enquiry and/or marketing by us (the “Purposes”), we may use, store or otherwise
       process your Personal Data, including:
       a - information provided by you to us in making any application for any service or Account,
       b - information provided by third parties (e.g. your employer, joint account holder or other
             organisations) and;
       c - information otherwise obtained in conjunction with your subsequent use of the Website or any services.
       You confirm that you are entitled to disclose information about any third party named on an application
       form. You freely consent to the processing and disclosure of your Personal Data for the Purposes.
Selftrade, Boatman’s House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA Tel: 0845 0700 720 Email: info@selftrade.co.uk www.selftrade.co.uk FS16 0914

       B - Purposes for which we may process your Personal Data
       The Purposes for which we may process your Personal Data include:
       a-p   roviding a Service to you, including administering your Account and any agreement between us for
            the provision of a Service;
       b - providing services ancillary to any such agreement or Service;
       c-w   here you have requested a service from third-party providers, introducing you to third-party
            providers (such as London Capital Group Limited) and sharing your Personal Data with such third-
            party providers for this purpose;
       d-u   nless you have specified that you do not wish to receive marketing communications from
            us, marketing to you of our financial services and products, or other products of a similar or
            complementary nature;
       e - t he release of your name, address, email address and telephone number to market research
            organisations for the purpose of confidential market research surveys carried out by post, telephone
            or electronically on Selftrade’s behalf;
       f - the compliance with a request you make of us;
       g-a   ssessment of financial standing and verification of identity checks, including that we may use the
            services of a credit reference agency such as Experian, or fraud prevention agencies;
       h - t he transfer of information to the Official Receiver or appointed insolvency practitioner(s) for
            the administration of your Account, if we receive notice of or are informed of your insolvency or
            bankruptcy, or of any insolvency proceedings/arrangements;
       i - e
             nforcing or obtaining settlement of debts owed to Selftrade or in relation to investments made on
            your behalf, including sharing your information with any debt collection, debt tracing or other agent
            for these purposes;
       j- a  ny use of your Personal Data to comply with legal or regulatory obligations, including disclosing
            Personal Data to a third party if we are required (or reasonably believe we are required) to do so by
            law, or if we are requested to disclose information to the Financial Conduct Authority, Prudential
            Regulation Authority, HM Revenue & Customs or any other regulatory or fiscal authority in any
            country, the London Stock Exchange plc, ICAP Securities and Derivatives Exchange Limited (ISDX) or
            the operator of any market on which you may hold investments;
       k - s haring with HMRC and/or any domestic and/or any foreign tax authority any information or
            documentation that you have provided to us with respect to your liability to tax in any jurisdiction
            (both within the UK and, if applicable, internationally) and/or in response to requests from such
            authorities; and
       l- w  here you have requested to take part in an initial placement offering (IPO), retail Bond offering,
            any similar offering, or hold any investment, we may provide such information relating to your
            request or holding as may be reasonably requested by the issuer of that investment, or any
            managers acting on their behalf, in connection with the offer or issue of that investment.
       You agree that the Purposes may be amended to include other uses or disclosures of Personal Data
       following notification to you by secure electronic message and by posting a notice on our Website.
       You will have the option to decline to have your personal data held for such changed Purposes by
       notifying us at info@selftrade.co.uk. We would remind customers that, by doing this, it may no longer
       be possible for Selftrade to provide our Services to you.
       C - When we may disclose information containing Personal Data to third parties
       We will not disclose any information which contains Personal Data we hold about you to anyone,
       except if:
       a - we do so for any of the Purposes set out above;
       b - we disclose it to a third party in any of the circumstances set out below;
       c - you give us consent to disclose the information;
       d-w   e believe we are legally required to disclose the information, or are allowed to do so under an
            exemption set out in the Act;
       e-w   e do so in connection with a transfer of rights and obligations under this Privacy Policy, any
            insurance policy or contract;
       f - we do so in the event that our business or its assets are sold or transferred; or
       g - our legitimate business interests require the disclosure of the information.
Selftrade, Boatman’s House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA Tel: 0845 0700 720 Email: info@selftrade.co.uk www.selftrade.co.uk FS16 0914

       We currently transfer information which contains Personal Data to Boursorama, Equiniti Financial
       Services Limited and Société Générale Securities Services, for the Purpose of providing services to
       our customers. We may transfer information which contains Personal Data to other or alternative
       third party providers to perform such services, or to a third party acting as our agent, where this is
       necessary for the Purpose of continuing to provide services to you.
       If we transfer or disclose information which contains Personal Data to a third party performing services
       for us or acting as our agent, including to our professional advisers and to third parties assisting in
       the administration of our services or the provision of other related services, your Personal Data will
       continue to be held in accordance with the requirements of the Act. Whether such third party is located
       in or outside of the United Kingdom, we will make sure that the third party agrees to apply the same
       levels of protection as we apply to your Personal Data.
       As a customer, or if you have registered for a Member Account, you have the ability to choose to make
       some of the content you may produce using the Member Services (such as forum posts and watchlists)
       viewable to other Members and Website visitors, or to keep it private. This does not include any
       Personal Data relating to your Account, which cannot be viewed by other Members.
       D - Transfer of Personal Data outside of the EEA
       For the Purposes described above, your Personal Data is processed in the European Economic Area
       (EEA). If necessary, it may be processed in countries outside the EEA which may not have the same
       data protection laws as the United Kingdom or other countries in the EEA. In the event it is necessary
       for us to transfer your Personal Data outside the EEA in order to provide the Services relating to your
       Account, we will ensure adequate safeguards are in place to protect your Personal Data before making
       the transfer, and will not transfer Personal Data if we cannot be sure it is sufficiently protected.
       E - How long we may hold Personal Data for
       Personal Data will be retained for a reasonable time after enquiries are received by Selftrade (whether
       or not an agreement is subsequently entered into) and/or for a reasonable time after any resultant
       action or agreement has expired. This extends to the retention of such information by Selftrade and/
       or any company within our Group. In addition, we are required by law or by rules made by the Financial
       Conduct Authority or Prudential Regulation Authority to retain certain types of information for
       specified time periods.
       F - Subject Access
       You have certain rights under the Act in relation to your Personal Data, known as Subject Access rights.
       These rights include, but are not limited to, the right to, upon payment of a fee, request a copy of the
       Personal Data we hold which relates to you. For more information on your rights and how to make a
       request, including to request a copy of your Personal Data, please see the ‘Subject Access Information’
       page of our Website.
       To make a Subject Access Request, please write to the Data Protection Officer at Selftrade, Boatman’s
       House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA enclosing a cheque for the fee. You may make a request
       in writing by secure electronic message, email or fax instead. We may have to ask you to provide
       evidence of your identity, or provide more information, before we can respond to your request.
       G - Monitoring
       For quality control, training and regulatory purposes, we may monitor and/or record your
       communications with us.
       4 - How we use cookies
       When you use our Website, information may be stored or accessed on your computer (known as
       “cookies”). Cookies are blocks of text placed in files on your computer’s hard drive when you visit a
       Website and which may contain information to identify you. Selftrade uses cookies to track our online
       marketing activity and to ensure that when you log in to the My Account secure area of the site, we
       maintain your confidentiality and security.
       For more information about how we use cookies, and your right to consent to their use, please see our
       Cookie Policy - (Please note that the Cookie Policy does not form part of this Privacy Policy or part of
       our Terms and Conditions).
Selftrade, Boatman’s House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA Tel: 0845 0700 720 Email: info@selftrade.co.uk www.selftrade.co.uk FS16 0914

       5 - Links to other websites
       We link to a wide variety of other sites and we may display advertisements from third parties on
       our Website. We are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of these sites and third-party
       advertisers, nor for the way in which information about their users is treated. In particular, unless
       expressly stated, we are not agents for these sites or advertisers nor are we authorised to make
       representations on their behalf.
Selftrade, Boatman’s House, 2 Selsdon Way, London E14 9LA Tel: 0845 0700 720 Email: info@selftrade.co.uk www.selftrade.co.uk FS16 0914
